<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Missing Features in OpenXML on Aspose.Cells Product Family</title>
    <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsforopenxml/missingfeaturesinopenxml/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Missing Features in OpenXML on Aspose.Cells Product Family</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsforopenxml/missingfeaturesinopenxml/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Calculate or Recalculate formulas dynamically</title>
      <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsforopenxml/missingfeaturesinopenxml/calculate&#43;or&#43;recalculate&#43;formulas&#43;dynamically/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsforopenxml/missingfeaturesinopenxml/calculate&#43;or&#43;recalculate&#43;formulas&#43;dynamically/</guid>
      <description>Formula calculation engine is embedded in Aspose.Cells. It can not only re-calculate the formula imported from the designer file but also supports to calculate the results of formulas added at runtime.
Adding Formulas &amp;amp; Calculating Results
Aspose.Cells supports most of the formulas or functions that are the part of Microsoft Excel. Developers can use these formulas using API or Designer Spreadsheets. Aspose.Excel supports a huge set of Mathematical, String, Boolean, Date/Time, Statistical, Database, Lookup and Reference formulas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert between Excel formats</title>
      <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsforopenxml/missingfeaturesinopenxml/convert&#43;between&#43;excel&#43;formats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsforopenxml/missingfeaturesinopenxml/convert&#43;between&#43;excel&#43;formats/</guid>
      <description>Converting Excel to PDF
PDF files are widely used for exchanging documents between organizations, government sectors and individuals. It is a standard document format and software developers are often asked to find a way to convert Microsoft Excel files into PDF documents. Aspose.Cells supports converting Excel files to PDF and maintains high visual fidelity in the conversion.
Aspose.Cells for .NET supports conversion from spreadsheets to PDF independently of other software. Save an Excel file to PDF using the Workbook class&amp;rsquo; Save method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encrypting Excel Files using Aspose.Cells</title>
      <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsforopenxml/missingfeaturesinopenxml/encrypting&#43;excel&#43;files&#43;using&#43;aspose.cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsforopenxml/missingfeaturesinopenxml/encrypting&#43;excel&#43;files&#43;using&#43;aspose.cells/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft Excel (97 - 2007) enables you to encrypt and password protect your spreadsheets. It uses algorithms provided by a cryptographic service provider, or CSP, a set of cryptographic algorithms with different properties. The default CSP is &amp;lsquo;Office 97/2000 Compatible&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Weak Encryption (XOR)&#39;. It&amp;rsquo;s important to choose the proper encryption key length. Some CSPs don&amp;rsquo;t support more than 40 or 56 bits. That&amp;rsquo;s considered to be a weak encryption. For strong encryption, a minimum key length of 128 bits is required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save Workbook to Text or CSV Format using Aspose.Cells</title>
      <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsforopenxml/missingfeaturesinopenxml/save&#43;workbook&#43;to&#43;text&#43;or&#43;csv&#43;format&#43;using&#43;aspose.cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsforopenxml/missingfeaturesinopenxml/save&#43;workbook&#43;to&#43;text&#43;or&#43;csv&#43;format&#43;using&#43;aspose.cells/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, you want to convert or save a workbook with multiple worksheets into text format. For text formats (for example TXT, TabDelim, CSV etc.), by default both Microsoft Excel and Aspose.Cells save the contents of the active worksheet only.
The following code example explains how to save an entire workbook into text format. Load the source workbook which could be any Microsoft Excel or OpenOffice spreadsheet file (so XLS, XLSX, XLSM, XLSB, ODS and so on) with any number of worksheets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set External Links in Formulas in Aspose.Cells</title>
      <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsforopenxml/missingfeaturesinopenxml/set&#43;external&#43;links&#43;in&#43;formulas&#43;in&#43;aspose.cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsforopenxml/missingfeaturesinopenxml/set&#43;external&#43;links&#43;in&#43;formulas&#43;in&#43;aspose.cells/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, it is necessary to include links to external files in formulas, for example to evaluate a cell or range value against them. Aspose.Cells provides this feature and this document explains how to use it.
The sample code below shows how to include external files in formulas.
C#
string FilePath = @&amp;quot;......\Sample Files&amp;quot;;
string FileName = FilePath + &amp;ldquo;Set External Links in Formula.xlsx&amp;rdquo;;
//Instantiate a new Workbook.
Workbook workbook = new Workbook();</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Formula Calculation Mode of Workbook in Aspose.Cells</title>
      <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsforopenxml/missingfeaturesinopenxml/setting&#43;formula&#43;calculation&#43;mode&#43;of&#43;workbook&#43;in&#43;aspose.cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsforopenxml/missingfeaturesinopenxml/setting&#43;formula&#43;calculation&#43;mode&#43;of&#43;workbook&#43;in&#43;aspose.cells/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft Excel allows you to set the formula calculation mode, that is, the way formulas are calculated. There are three possible values:
 Automatic - recalculate whenever something is changed, and every time a workbook is opened. Automatic except for data tables - recalculate whenever something is changed, but leaving out data tables. Manual - recalculate only when the user explicitly requests it by pressing F9 or CTRL+ALT+F9, or when the workbook is saved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Shared Formula in Aspose.Cells</title>
      <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsforopenxml/missingfeaturesinopenxml/setting&#43;shared&#43;formula&#43;in&#43;aspose.cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsforopenxml/missingfeaturesinopenxml/setting&#43;shared&#43;formula&#43;in&#43;aspose.cells/</guid>
      <description>Suppose you have a worksheet filled with data.
You want to add a function in B2 that will calculate the sales tax for the first row of data. The tax is 9%. The formula that calculates the sales tax is: &amp;ldquo;=A2*0.09&amp;rdquo;. This article explains how to apply this formula with Aspose.Cells.
Aspose.Cells lets you specify a formula using the Cell.Formula property.
There are two options for adding formulas to the other cells (B3, B4, B5, and so on) in the column.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>