<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Working with Cells on Aspose.Cells Product Family</title>
    <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Working with Cells on Aspose.Cells Product Family</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessing Cells in a Worksheet</title>
      <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/accessing&#43;cells&#43;in&#43;a&#43;worksheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/accessing&#43;cells&#43;in&#43;a&#43;worksheet/</guid>
      <description>We have discussed about working with worksheets, rows and columns so far but this is the time to go more deeper and talk about cells. So, in this topic, we would start our discussion about cells with a basic feature of accessing cells.
   Contents Summary
1 Accessing Cells in a Worksheet 1.1 Using Cell Name
1.2 Using Cell&amp;rsquo;s Row and Column Indices
1.3 Getting Focused Cell
 ||      Accessing Cells in a Worksheet      We can access any cell of a worksheet using the API of Aspose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessing and Modifying the Value of a Cell</title>
      <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/accessing&#43;&#43;and&#43;&#43;modifying&#43;the&#43;value&#43;of&#43;a&#43;cell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/accessing&#43;&#43;and&#43;&#43;modifying&#43;the&#43;value&#43;of&#43;a&#43;cell/</guid>
      <description>In our previous topic, we have discussed about accessing cells of a worksheet. In this topic, we will simply extend that topic to show developers that how can they access and modify the values of cells using the API of Aspose.Cells.GridDesktop.
Access and Modify Cell Value using Aspose.Cells.GridDesktop
Before accessing and modifying the value of a cell, we should know that how to access cells. There are three approaches to access cells of a worksheet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Formulas to Cells</title>
      <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/adding&#43;formulas&#43;to&#43;cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/adding&#43;formulas&#43;to&#43;cells/</guid>
      <description>A cell cannot only just contain a simple value like a numeric figure or some text but we can also insert a formula in a cell as its value. A formula is used in a cell when the value of a cell needs to be determined after some calculations. In this topic, we will discuss that how can we access and modify a formula applied on a cell.
Adding Formula to a Cell</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing the Font and Color of a Cell</title>
      <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/changing&#43;the&#43;font&#43;and&#43;color&#43;of&#43;a&#43;cell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/changing&#43;the&#43;font&#43;and&#43;color&#43;of&#43;a&#43;cell/</guid>
      <description>In this topic, we will discuss about changing the font and font color of a cell. This feature provides more in depth control of worksheets to developers. Using this feature, developers can customize the font and color of any desired cell.
Changing the Font &amp;amp; Color of a Cell
To change the font and color of a cell using Aspose.Cells.GridDesktop, please follow the steps below:
 Access any desired Worksheet Access a Cell whose font and color are to be changed Create a customized Font Set the Font of the Cell to the customized one Finally, set Font Color of the Cell to any desired Color  \</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applying Styles on Cells</title>
      <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/applying&#43;styles&#43;on&#43;cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/applying&#43;styles&#43;on&#43;cells/</guid>
      <description>This topic deals with applying styles on cells so, we will try to cover almost everything that can be used to apply style on a cell. Besides some basic formatting settings, we will also discuss about drawing borders and setting number format of cells in detail.
   Contents Summary
1 Applying a Custom Style on a Cell - An Example
2 Drawing Borders of Cells 2.1 Types of Borders</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formatting a Range of Cells</title>
      <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/formatting&#43;a&#43;range&#43;of&#43;cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/formatting&#43;a&#43;range&#43;of&#43;cells/</guid>
      <description>This topic also belongs to the series of topics related to the application of font settings and other formatting styles on cells. Our last topics have covered well about handling such features. For example, you can refer to Changing the Font &amp;amp; Color of a Cell and Applying Styles on Cells topics to learn about the same features. Then what is new in this topic if we have already covered these concepts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Style Dialog</title>
      <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/using&#43;style&#43;dialog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/using&#43;style&#43;dialog/</guid>
      <description>Aspose.Cells.GridDesktop is a GUI based control that lets its users to work on their data in a WYSIWYG mode. We have explored the API of Aspose.Cells.GridDesktop a lot to perform different kinds of tasks. We have also discussed about controlling the formatting settings of Grid, Worksheets, Rows &amp;amp; Columns and Cells programmatically using the robust and easier API of Aspose.Cells.GridDesktop. But all of that was from the programming point of view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Format Painter</title>
      <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/using&#43;format&#43;painter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/using&#43;format&#43;painter/</guid>
      <description>Format painter is the feature of MS Excel that has been adapted in Aspose.Cells.GridDesktop. It&amp;rsquo;s a very nice feature. For those people who have not yet used this feature, format painter allows users to apply the formatting settings of any focused cell to another cell. The implementation of this feature is very simple. In this topic, we will cover that too.
   Contents Summary
1 Using Format Painter 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merging and Unmerging Cells</title>
      <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/merging&#43;&#43;and&#43;&#43;unmerging&#43;cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/merging&#43;&#43;and&#43;&#43;unmerging&#43;cells/</guid>
      <description>In this topic, we will discuss a utility feature of merging and unmerging cells of a worksheet. This feature is useful in those cases when we need to span some rows or columns to enhance the readability of data.
   Contents Summary
1 Merging Cells
2 Unmerging Cells
 ||      Merging Cells      To merge cells into a single large cell, please follow the steps below:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filtering Data</title>
      <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/filtering&#43;data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/filtering&#43;data/</guid>
      <description>Aspose.Cells.GridDesktop provides Auto-Filter and Custom Data Filter features for the users. Using these features, you may find a way to select only those items from the worksheet that you want to display in a list. Moreover, you are allowed to filter items in a list according to a set criteria. You can filter text, numbers or dates with Auto-Filter / Custom Data Filter feature.
You can use EnableAutoFilter Boolean attribute of RowFilterSettings class to enable the Auto-Filter feature for the GridDesktop control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Named Ranges</title>
      <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/using&#43;named&#43;ranges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/using&#43;named&#43;ranges/</guid>
      <description>Normally, you use the labels of columns and rows on a worksheet to refer to the cells within those columns and rows. But you can create descriptive names to represent cells, ranges of cells, formulas, or constant values. The word Name may refer to a string of characters that represents a cell, range of cells, formula, or constant value. For example, Use easy-to-understand names, such as Products, to refer to hard to understand ranges, such as Sales!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Undo and Redo Feature</title>
      <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/using&#43;undo&#43;and&#43;redo&#43;feature/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/using&#43;undo&#43;and&#43;redo&#43;feature/</guid>
      <description>The GridDesktop&amp;rsquo;s Undo/Redo feature is very useful. The name explains its functionality itselft, it allows you to undo/redo the recent action(s) in a worksheet. For example, if a formula is accidentally deleted or you edit data in a cell which you don&amp;rsquo;t actually want, these actions can be corrected by using the Undo and Redo operations provided by the control.
   Contents Summary
1 Performing Undo and Redo Operation 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Cell Protection in Worksheet</title>
      <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/adding&#43;cell&#43;protection&#43;in&#43;worksheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/adding&#43;cell&#43;protection&#43;in&#43;worksheet/</guid>
      <description>Aspose.Cells for GridDesktop allows you to protect your cells in a worksheet. You first need to protect your worksheet, then you can protect your desired cells in a worksheet. In order to protect worksheet, please set Worksheet.Protected property to true, then use Worksheet.SetProtected() method to protect the range of cells.
Protect Cell using Aspose.Cells.GridDesktop
The following sample code protects all the cells in range A1:B1 of the active worksheet of GridDesktop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text overflows from GridDesktop cell if it is too long</title>
      <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/text&#43;overflows&#43;from&#43;griddesktop&#43;cell&#43;if&#43;it&#43;is&#43;too&#43;long/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roywangt.github.io/cellsnet/developerguide/asposecellsgriddesktop/workingwithcells/text&#43;overflows&#43;from&#43;griddesktop&#43;cell&#43;if&#43;it&#43;is&#43;too&#43;long/</guid>
      <description>Contents Summary
1 Possible Usage Scenarios
2 Text overflows from GridDesktop cell if it is too long
3 Screenshot
 |     Possible Usage Scenarios     Microsoft Excel overflows the text when the next adjacent cells are empty and the text is too long to fit inside the cell. Aspose.Cells for GridDesktop also supports this feature. However, this feature was not supported in earlier versions of GridDesktop e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>