<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rendering and Printing on Aspose.Cells Product Family</title>
    <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rendering and Printing on Aspose.Cells Product Family</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Print Comments while saving to PDF</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/print&#43;comments&#43;while&#43;saving&#43;to&#43;pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/print&#43;comments&#43;while&#43;saving&#43;to&#43;pdf/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft Excel allows you to print comments while printing or saving to PDF format with the following options
 None At end of sheet As displayed on sheet  Aspose.Cells provide the PrintCommentsType enum to support the same feature. The PrintCommentsType enum has the following members
 PrintNoComments PrintInPlace PrintSheetEnd  Print Comments while saving to PDF
The following sample code illustrates how to use PrintCommentsType to print comments while saving to PDF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert an Excel Chart to Image</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/convert&#43;an&#43;excel&#43;chart&#43;to&#43;image/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/convert&#43;an&#43;excel&#43;chart&#43;to&#43;image/</guid>
      <description>Charts are visually appealing and make it easy for users to see comparisons, patterns, and trends in data. For instance, rather than analyzing columns of worksheet numbers, a chart shows at a glance whether sales are falling or rising, or how actual sales compare to projected sales. People are frequently asked to present statistical and graphical information in an easy to understand and an easy to maintain manner. A picture helps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert an XLS File to PDF Format</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/convert&#43;an&#43;xls&#43;file&#43;to&#43;pdf&#43;format/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/convert&#43;an&#43;xls&#43;file&#43;to&#43;pdf&#43;format/</guid>
      <description>PDF (Portable Document Format) represents documents independently of the software, hardware, and operating system used to create those documents. A PDF file can be documents with any combination of text, graphics, and images in a device-independent and resolution-independent manner. PDF files are often compressed, so they take up less space than the original file.
At times, you need to convert a Microsoft Excel file to PDF. For this, you require a fast, secure, accurate and reliable solution that lets you distribute PDF documents around the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worksheet to Image - Remove Whitespace around Data</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/worksheet&#43;to&#43;image&#43;-&#43;remove&#43;whitespace&#43;around&#43;data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/worksheet&#43;to&#43;image&#43;-&#43;remove&#43;whitespace&#43;around&#43;data/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, you need to present worksheet images in applications or web pages. For example, you might need to insert images into a Word document, a PDF file, a PowerPoint presentation or some other document. Basically, you want to render a worksheet as an image so that it can be pasted into other applications. Aspose.Cells allows you to convert Microsoft Excel worksheets to images.
Remove Whitespace around Data
The Aspose.Cells.Rendering.SheetRender API converts a worksheet to an image file with any specified attributes, for example, image format, paginated sheets, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert XLS File with Images or Charts to PDF</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/convert&#43;xls&#43;file&#43;with&#43;images&#43;or&#43;charts&#43;to&#43;pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/convert&#43;xls&#43;file&#43;with&#43;images&#43;or&#43;charts&#43;to&#43;pdf/</guid>
      <description>Aspose.Cells supports converting XLS files that contain images and charts to PDF documents. Aspose.Cells for .NET can work independently to convert a spreadsheet to PDF: Aspose.PDF for .NET is not required for the conversion. The process can be done in memory as the process does not depend on temporary or intermediary XML files. This means that large Excel files, for example, ones containing images, charts, and other drawing objects, can be converted quickly and efficiently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Page Setup and Printing Options</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/page&#43;setup&#43;and&#43;printing&#43;options/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/page&#43;setup&#43;and&#43;printing&#43;options/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, developers need to configure page setup and print settings to control the printing process. Page setup and print settings offer various options and are fully supported in Aspose.Cells.
This article shows how to create a console application in Visual Studio.Net, and apply page setup and printing options to a worksheet with a few simple lines of code using the Aspose.Cells API.
   Contents Summary
1 Working with Page and Print Settings 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Printing Workbooks</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/printing&#43;workbooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/printing&#43;workbooks/</guid>
      <description>After creating a worksheet, you often want to print a hard copy of it. This article explains how to print spreadsheets with Aspose.Cells.
   Contents Summary
1 Introduction 1.1 Print Using SheetRender
1.2 Print Using WorkbookRender
 ||      Introduction      Microsoft Excel assumes that you want to print the entire worksheet area unless you specify a selection. To print using Aspose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting Worksheet to Image and Worksheet to Image by Page</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/converting&#43;worksheet&#43;to&#43;image&#43;and&#43;worksheet&#43;to&#43;image&#43;by&#43;page/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/converting&#43;worksheet&#43;to&#43;image&#43;and&#43;worksheet&#43;to&#43;image&#43;by&#43;page/</guid>
      <description>This document is designed to provide the developers with a detailed understanding on how to convert a worksheet to an image file &amp;amp; worksheet with multiple pages to an image file per page.
Sometimes, you might need to present worksheets as images, for example to use them in applications or web pages. You might need to insert the images into a Word document, a PDF file, a PowerPoint presentation or use them in some other scenario.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting Worksheet to Image using ImageOrPrint Options</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/converting&#43;worksheet&#43;to&#43;image&#43;using&#43;imageorprint&#43;options/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/converting&#43;worksheet&#43;to&#43;image&#43;using&#43;imageorprint&#43;options/</guid>
      <description>This document is designed to provide a detailed understanding of how to convert a worksheet to an image file and apply different image and print options for the image, options like resolution, TIFF compression, image format and page quality.
   Contents Summary
1 Saving Worksheets to Images - Different Approaches
2 Using Aspose.Cells to Convert Worksheet to Image using ImageOrPrint options. 2.1 Creating a template workbook in Microsoft Excel</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Render One Pdf Page Per Excel Worksheet - Excel to Pdf Conversion</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/render&#43;one&#43;pdf&#43;page&#43;per&#43;excel&#43;worksheet&#43;-&#43;excel&#43;to&#43;pdf&#43;conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/render&#43;one&#43;pdf&#43;page&#43;per&#43;excel&#43;worksheet&#43;-&#43;excel&#43;to&#43;pdf&#43;conversion/</guid>
      <description>When working with large Microsoft Excel files (for example a workbook that has many sheets, each with 50 columns and 300 or more rows of data), you might want the PDF output to show one page per worksheet, regardless of the size of the worksheet. This would mean that each page is likely to have a radically different page size. This can be achieved by using Aspose.Cells for .NET.
Please see the following sample code that converts an Excel file with multiple worksheets to PDF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate Thumbnail of the Worksheet</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/generate&#43;thumbnail&#43;of&#43;the&#43;worksheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/generate&#43;thumbnail&#43;of&#43;the&#43;worksheet/</guid>
      <description>It can be useful to generate thumbnails from worksheets. A thumbnail is a small image that can be pasted into a Word document or a PowerPoint presentation to give a preview of what&amp;rsquo;s on the worksheet. It can be added to a webpage with a link to download the original document and has a host of other uses.
Aspose.Cells for .NET allows you to output worksheets to image files so making a thumbnail is easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure PDF Documents</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/secure&#43;pdf&#43;documents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/secure&#43;pdf&#43;documents/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, developers need to work with encrypted PDF files. For example, they need to secure documents with user and owner passwords so not just anyone can open them, or want to restrict whether the document content can be printed or extracted.
This article explains how to pass in PDF security options when saving spreadsheets to PDF.
Aspose.Cells provides the Aspose.Cells.Rendering.PdfSecurity namespace for working with security. The sample code below describes how to secure PDFs with Aspose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save Each Worksheet to a Different PDF File</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/save&#43;each&#43;worksheet&#43;to&#43;a&#43;different&#43;pdf&#43;file/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/save&#43;each&#43;worksheet&#43;to&#43;a&#43;different&#43;pdf&#43;file/</guid>
      <description>Aspose.Cells supports converting XLS files (that contain images, charts, etc.) to PDF documents. Aspose.Cells for .NET can work independently to convert a spreadsheet to PDF and you do not need to use Aspose.PDF for .NET for the conversion. The conversion does not require the software to create or use any temporary files as the whole process can be done in memory.
Save Each Worksheet to a Different PDF File
If you need to save each worksheet in your template Excel file to generate different PDF files, you can achieve this easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extract Images from Worksheets using ImageOrPrintOptions</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/extract&#43;images&#43;from&#43;worksheets&#43;using&#43;imageorprintoptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/extract&#43;images&#43;from&#43;worksheets&#43;using&#43;imageorprintoptions/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft Excel users can add images to spreadsheets. With Aspose.Cells, it&amp;rsquo;s possible to read images from Microsoft Excel files and save them to a local drive. This article shows how.
The sample code below shows how to extract images from an Excel file and save them.
\</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resampling Added Images - Excel to PDF Conversion</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/resampling&#43;added&#43;images&#43;-&#43;excel&#43;to&#43;pdf&#43;conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/resampling&#43;added&#43;images&#43;-&#43;excel&#43;to&#43;pdf&#43;conversion/</guid>
      <description>While working with big Microsoft Excel files with lots of images, you might need to compress images that have been added to reduce the output PDF file size and improve the overall conversion performance. Aspose.Cells supports resampling added images to reduce the output PDF file size and improve the performance somewhat.
Example
Please see the following sample code that describes how to perform the task using the Aspose.Cells API. The example converts a Microsoft Excel file to a PDF file while compressing the images in the file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fit All Worksheet Columns on Single PDF Page</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/fit&#43;all&#43;worksheet&#43;columns&#43;on&#43;single&#43;pdf&#43;page/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/fit&#43;all&#43;worksheet&#43;columns&#43;on&#43;single&#43;pdf&#43;page/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you want to generate a PDF file that fits all a worksheet&amp;rsquo;s columns onto one page. The PdfSaveOptions.AllColumnsInOnePagePerSheet property provides this feature in a very easy-to-use manner. Complex calculations such as the height and width of the output PDF are handled internally and are based on the data in the worksheet.
Resources
Below are the input spreadsheet used in the example and output PDF generated for reference.
 Excel File (Input) PDF File (Output)  Fit Worksheet Columns on Single PDF Page</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Transparent Image of Excel Worksheet</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/create&#43;transparent&#43;image&#43;of&#43;excel&#43;worksheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/create&#43;transparent&#43;image&#43;of&#43;excel&#43;worksheet/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, you need to generate the image of your worksheet as transparent image. You want to apply transparency to all cells which have no fill colors. Aspose.Cells provides the ImageOrPrintOptions.Transparent property to apply transparency to worksheet image. When this property is false, then cells with no fill colors are drawn with white color and when it is true, cells with no fill colors are drawn transparent.
In the following worksheet image, transparency has not been applied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limit the Number of Pages Generated - Excel to PDF Conversion</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/limit&#43;the&#43;number&#43;of&#43;pages&#43;generated&#43;-&#43;excel&#43;to&#43;pdf&#43;conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/limit&#43;the&#43;number&#43;of&#43;pages&#43;generated&#43;-&#43;excel&#43;to&#43;pdf&#43;conversion/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, you want to print a range of pages to an output PDF file. Aspose.Cells has the ability to set a limit on how many pages are generated when converting an Excel spreadsheet to the PDF file format.
Limiting the Number of Pages Generated
The following example shows how to render a range of pages (3 and 4) in a Microsoft Excel file to PDF.
\
If the spreadsheet contains formulas, it is best to call Workbook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find Cells with Specific Style</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/find&#43;cells&#43;with&#43;specific&#43;style/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/find&#43;cells&#43;with&#43;specific&#43;style/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, you need to find cells with a particular style applied. You can use Aspose.Cells to find all cells with a common style. Aspose.Cells provides the FindOptions.Style property which you can use to specify the style to search cells for.
The code in this example finds all cells that have the same style as that of cell A1. After the code has been executed, all the cells that have the same style as A1 contain the text &amp;ldquo;Found&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worksheet to Image - Set Pixel Format for the Rendered Image</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/worksheet&#43;to&#43;image&#43;-&#43;set&#43;pixel&#43;format&#43;for&#43;the&#43;rendered&#43;image/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/worksheet&#43;to&#43;image&#43;-&#43;set&#43;pixel&#43;format&#43;for&#43;the&#43;rendered&#43;image/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you want to specify the pixel format when rendering a worksheet to image format. By default, Aspose.Cells uses 32 bits per pixel. Aspose.Cells allows you to customize the pixel format (bit depth) using options for the rendered image.
Please see the sample code below that demonstrates how to set the desired pixel format while rendering images of the sheets.
\</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prevent Exporting Hidden Worksheet Contents on Saving to HTML</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/prevent&#43;exporting&#43;hidden&#43;worksheet&#43;contents&#43;on&#43;saving&#43;to&#43;html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/prevent&#43;exporting&#43;hidden&#43;worksheet&#43;contents&#43;on&#43;saving&#43;to&#43;html/</guid>
      <description>You can save Excel workbooks to HTML. However, if the workbook contains hidden worksheets, Aspose.Cells by default exports the hidden worksheet contents to the HTML output (_files) directory which contains files such as worksheets, images, tabstrip.htm, stylesheet.css etc. Sometimes, exporting the hidden worksheets content this way isn&amp;rsquo;t appropriate. For example, if the hidden worksheet contains images that should not be exported to the _files directory.
Aspose.Cells provides the HtmlSaveOptions.ExportHiddenWorksheet property. By default, it is set to true and hidden worksheets are exported to HTML.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excel to HTML - Use PresentationPreference Option for Better Layout</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/excel&#43;to&#43;html&#43;-&#43;use&#43;presentationpreference&#43;option&#43;for&#43;better&#43;layout/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/excel&#43;to&#43;html&#43;-&#43;use&#43;presentationpreference&#43;option&#43;for&#43;better&#43;layout/</guid>
      <description>Aspose.Cells provides a useful HtmlSaveOptions.PresentationPreference property for developers who need to render better layout when saving a Microsoft Excel file to HTML or MHT format. The default value of the property is false. We recommend setting this property to true to get a more attractive presentation of Excel reports.
Please see the sample code below that demonstrates how to render an HTML file from Excel report with presentation preference on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Warnings for Font Substitution while Rendering Excel File</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/get&#43;warnings&#43;for&#43;font&#43;substitution&#43;while&#43;rendering&#43;excel&#43;file/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/get&#43;warnings&#43;for&#43;font&#43;substitution&#43;while&#43;rendering&#43;excel&#43;file/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, when rendering a Microsoft Excel file to PDF, Aspose.Cells substitutes fonts. Aspose.Cells provides a feature that lets developers know what particular font has been substituted by firing a warning. This is a useful feature that can help you identify why an Aspose.Cells rendered PDF looks different from the original Microsoft Excel file so you can take appropriate actions. For example, installing the missing fonts so that rendering results look the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting Chart to Image in SVG Format</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/converting&#43;chart&#43;to&#43;image&#43;in&#43;svg&#43;format/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/converting&#43;chart&#43;to&#43;image&#43;in&#43;svg&#43;format/</guid>
      <description>Scalable Vector Graphics (SVG) is an XML-based vector image format for two-dimensional graphics that also supports interactivity and animation. The SVG specification is an open standard developed by the World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) since 1999.
SVG images and their behaviors are defined in XML text files. This means that they can be searched, indexed, scripted, and compressed. As XML files, SVG images can be created and edited with any text editor, but are more often created with drawing software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Printing Range of Pages using SheetRender and WorkbookRender</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/printing&#43;range&#43;of&#43;pages&#43;using&#43;sheetrender&#43;and&#43;workbookrender/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/printing&#43;range&#43;of&#43;pages&#43;using&#43;sheetrender&#43;and&#43;workbookrender/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft Excel allows you to print range of pages of workbook or worksheet. The following screenshot shows the Microsoft Excel interface to specify the range of pages.
Aspose.Cells provides the WorkbookRender.ToPrinter(string PrinterName, int PrintPageIndex, int PrintPageCount) and SheetRender.ToPrinter(string PrinterName, int PrintPageIndex, int PrintPageCount) methods for this purpose.
Microsoft Excel Interface to specify the Range of Pages to Print
The following sample code illustrates the use of WorkbookRender.ToPrinter(string PrinterName, int PrintPageIndex, int PrintPageCount) and SheetRender.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change the Font on just the specific Unicode characters while saving to PDF</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/change&#43;the&#43;font&#43;on&#43;just&#43;the&#43;specific&#43;unicode&#43;characters&#43;while&#43;saving&#43;to&#43;pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/change&#43;the&#43;font&#43;on&#43;just&#43;the&#43;specific&#43;unicode&#43;characters&#43;while&#43;saving&#43;to&#43;pdf/</guid>
      <description>Some Unicode characters are not displayable by the user specified font. One such Unicode character is Non-breaking Hyphen (U+2011) and its Unicode number is 8209. This character cannot be displayed with Times New Roman, but it can be displayed with other fonts like Arial Unicode MS.
When such a character occurs inside some word or sentence which is in some specific font like Times New Roman, then Aspose.Cells changes the font of entire word or sentence to font which could display this character like Arial Unicode to MS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Specify Job or Document Name while printing with Aspose.Cells</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/specify&#43;job&#43;or&#43;document&#43;name&#43;while&#43;printing&#43;with&#43;aspose.cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/specify&#43;job&#43;or&#43;document&#43;name&#43;while&#43;printing&#43;with&#43;aspose.cells/</guid>
      <description>You can specify Job or Document Name while printing your workbook or worksheet using the WorkbookRender or SheetRender objects. Aspose.Cells provides the WorkbookRender.ToPrinter(printerName, jobName) and SheetRender.ToPrinter(printerName, jobName) methods which you can use to specify Job Name while printing your workbook or worksheet
Specify Job or Document Name while printing with Aspose.Cells
The sample code loads the source Excel file and then sends it to printer by specifying the job or document name using the WorkbookRender.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Export Chart to SVG with viewBox attribute</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/export&#43;chart&#43;to&#43;svg&#43;with&#43;viewbox&#43;attribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/export&#43;chart&#43;to&#43;svg&#43;with&#43;viewbox&#43;attribute/</guid>
      <description>By default, when chart is export to svg format, viewBox attribute is not included in its xml. However, Aspose.Cells provides ImageOrPrintOptions.SVGFitToViewPort property which when set to true exports the chart to svg with viewBox attribute.
Export Chart to SVG with viewBox attribute
The following sample code exports the chart to svg format with viewBox attribute.
\
If you open the chart&amp;rsquo;s svg in notepad, you will find the viewBox attribute similar to this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Export Worksheet or Chart into Image with Desired Width and Height</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/export&#43;worksheet&#43;or&#43;chart&#43;into&#43;image&#43;with&#43;desired&#43;width&#43;and&#43;height/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/export&#43;worksheet&#43;or&#43;chart&#43;into&#43;image&#43;with&#43;desired&#43;width&#43;and&#43;height/</guid>
      <description>You can use Aspose.Cells to export your worksheet or chart into image with desired width and height. It provides ImageOrPrintOptions.SetDesiredSize() method to set the desired width and height of the exported image. The width and height are specified in unit of pixels.
Export Worksheet into Image with Desired Width and Height
The following code exports the worksheet into image with 400x400 size.
\</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Render Worksheet to Graphic Context</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/render&#43;worksheet&#43;to&#43;graphic&#43;context/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/render&#43;worksheet&#43;to&#43;graphic&#43;context/</guid>
      <description>Aspose.Cells can now render worksheet to graphic context. Graphic context can be anything like image file, screen or printer etc. Please use one of the following two methods to render worksheet to graphic context.
 SheetRender.ToImage(int pageIndex, Graphics g, float x, float y) SheetRender.ToImage(int pageIndex, Graphics g, float x, float y, float width, float height)  Render Worksheet to Graphic Context
The following code illustrates how to use Aspose.Cells to render worksheet to graphic context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disable Exporting Frame Scripts and Document Properties</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/disable&#43;exporting&#43;frame&#43;scripts&#43;and&#43;document&#43;properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/disable&#43;exporting&#43;frame&#43;scripts&#43;and&#43;document&#43;properties/</guid>
      <description>Aspose.Cells exports frame scripts and document properties while converting a workbook into HTML. The 8.6.0 version of Aspose.Cells for .NET introduces an option which allows you optionally disable exporting frame scripts and doctment properties. Please use the HtmlSaveOptions.ExportFrameScriptsAndProperties property to disable the export.
Disable exporting frame scripts and document properties
The following sample code allows you to disable exporting frame scripts and document properties. Once you convert a workbook into HTML, the output file will not contain any frame scripts and document properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change the HTML Link Target Type</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/change&#43;the&#43;html&#43;link&#43;target&#43;type/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/change&#43;the&#43;html&#43;link&#43;target&#43;type/</guid>
      <description>Aspose.Cells allows you to change the HTML link target type. HTML link looks like this
As you can see the target attribute in above html link is _self. You can control this target attribute using the HtmlSaveOptions.LinkTargetType property. This property takes the HtmlLinkTargetType enum which has the following values.
 HtmlLinkTargetType.Blank HtmlLinkTargetType.Parent HtmlLinkTargetType.Self HtmlLinkTargetType.Top  Change the HTML Link Target Type
The following code illustrates the usage of HtmlSaveOptions.LinkTargetType property. It changes the link target type to blank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ignore Hidden Columns while Exporting Worksheet Data to Data Table</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/ignore&#43;hidden&#43;columns&#43;while&#43;exporting&#43;worksheet&#43;data&#43;to&#43;data&#43;table/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/ignore&#43;hidden&#43;columns&#43;while&#43;exporting&#43;worksheet&#43;data&#43;to&#43;data&#43;table/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, you want to ignore hidden columns while exporting worksheet data to data table. You can achieve it using Aspose.Cells by setting the ExportTableOptions.PlotVisibleColumns true. By default, its value is false, so you need to set it true to ignore the hidden columns.
Ignore Hidden Columns while Exporting Worksheet Data to Data Table
The following sample code explains the usage of ExportTableOptions.PlotVisibleColumns property in ignoring the hidden columns while exporting the worksheet entire data to data table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save Excel into PDF with Standard or Minimum Size</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/save&#43;excel&#43;into&#43;pdf&#43;with&#43;standard&#43;or&#43;minimum&#43;size/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/save&#43;excel&#43;into&#43;pdf&#43;with&#43;standard&#43;or&#43;minimum&#43;size/</guid>
      <description>By default, Aspose.Cells saves Excel into PDF with Standard size. However you can also save it with Minimum size using the PdfSaveOptions.OptimizationType property. It accepts the following values
 PdfOptimizationType.Standard PdfOptimizationType.MinimumSize  Save Excel into PDF with Standard or Minimum Size using Aspose.Cells
The following sample code shows how you can save Excel into PDF with Standard or Minimum size using PdfSaveOptions.OptimizationType property.
\
Attachments: standard-or-minimum-size.png (image/png)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Render Unicode Supplementary characters in output Pdf by Aspose.Cells</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/render&#43;unicode&#43;supplementary&#43;characters&#43;in&#43;output&#43;pdf&#43;by&#43;aspose.cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/render&#43;unicode&#43;supplementary&#43;characters&#43;in&#43;output&#43;pdf&#43;by&#43;aspose.cells/</guid>
      <description>Normal Unicode characters are 2-bytes long while Unicode Supplementary characters are 4-bytes long. Aspose.Cells now supports rendering of these 4-bytes Unicode characters.
In the Unicode Character Standard, Supplementary Characters are the characters assigned code points from U+10000 to U+10FFFF. In other words, these are the Unicode characters greater than U+FFFF.
 In UTF-8 these characters are each 4 bytes long. In UTF-16 these characters require 2 surrogates (16-bit units).     Contents Summary</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set Default Font while rendering spreadsheet to images</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/set&#43;default&#43;font&#43;while&#43;rendering&#43;spreadsheet&#43;to&#43;images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/set&#43;default&#43;font&#43;while&#43;rendering&#43;spreadsheet&#43;to&#43;images/</guid>
      <description>Please use the ImageOrPrintOptions.DefaultFont property to set the default font while rendering spreadsheet to images. This property will only be effective when the default font of workbook could not render your characters. The default font specified with ImageOrPrintOptions.DefaultFont property is used for all those cells which have invalid or non-existent fonts.
Set Default Font while rendering spreadsheet to images
The following sample code creates a workbook, adds some text in cell A4 of first worksheet and sets its font to invalid or non-existent font.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set Default Font while rendering spreadsheet to HTML</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/set&#43;default&#43;font&#43;while&#43;rendering&#43;spreadsheet&#43;to&#43;html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/developerguide/technicalarticles/asposecellsgeneral/renderingandprinting/set&#43;default&#43;font&#43;while&#43;rendering&#43;spreadsheet&#43;to&#43;html/</guid>
      <description>Aspose.Cells allows you to set default font while rendering spreadsheet to HTML. Please use the HtmlSaveOptions.DefaultFontName for this purpose. This property is useful when there are some cells in spreadsheet that has invalid or non-existing fonts. Then those cells will be rendered in a font specified with HtmlSaveOptions.DefaultFontName property.
Set Default Font while rendering spreadsheet to HTML
The following sample code creates a workbook and adds some text in cell B4 of first worksheet and sets its font to some unknown/non-existing font.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>