<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Missing Features in VSTO on Aspose.Cells Product Family</title>
    <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsnetforvsto/missingfeaturesinvsto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Missing Features in VSTO on Aspose.Cells Product Family</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsnetforvsto/missingfeaturesinvsto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Hyperlinks to Link Data in Aspose.Cells</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsnetforvsto/missingfeaturesinvsto/adding&#43;hyperlinks&#43;to&#43;link&#43;data&#43;in&#43;aspose.cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsnetforvsto/missingfeaturesinvsto/adding&#43;hyperlinks&#43;to&#43;link&#43;data&#43;in&#43;aspose.cells/</guid>
      <description>A hyperlink is used to create a link between two entities. Everybody is familiar with the use of hyperlinks, especially on websites.
Using Aspose.Cells, developers can create different kinds of hyperlinks in Microsoft Excel files. This topic discusses what types of hyperlinks are supported by Aspose.Cells and how they can be used in our Excel files.
Adding Hyperlinks
Three types of hyperlink can be added to a cell using Aspose.Cells:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Protection Settings since Excel XP in Aspose.Cells</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsnetforvsto/missingfeaturesinvsto/advanced&#43;protection&#43;settings&#43;since&#43;excel&#43;xp&#43;in&#43;aspose.cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsnetforvsto/missingfeaturesinvsto/advanced&#43;protection&#43;settings&#43;since&#43;excel&#43;xp&#43;in&#43;aspose.cells/</guid>
      <description>Delete rows or columns. Edit contents, objects or scenarios. Format cells, rows or columns. Insert rows, columns or hyperlinks. Select locked or unlocked cells. Use pivot tables and much more.  Aspose.Cells supports all the advanced protection settings offered by Excel XP or later versions.
Advanced Protection Settings Using Excel XP and Later Versions
To view the protection settings available in Excel XP:
  From the Tools menu, select Protection followed by Protect Sheet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversion</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsnetforvsto/missingfeaturesinvsto/conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsnetforvsto/missingfeaturesinvsto/conversion/</guid>
      <description>Aspose.Cells unique feature that provide flexibility in version conversions without affecting work. SaveFormat is enumeration that can convert document in the extensions given below in table.
   **Member Name ** **Value ** **Description **     CSV 1 Represents a CSV file.   Xlsx 6 Represents an xlsx file.   Xlsm 7 Represents an xlsm file which enable macros.   Xltx 8 Represents an xltx file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Display or Hide Gridlines in Aspose.Cells</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsnetforvsto/missingfeaturesinvsto/display&#43;or&#43;hide&#43;gridlines&#43;in&#43;aspose.cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsnetforvsto/missingfeaturesinvsto/display&#43;or&#43;hide&#43;gridlines&#43;in&#43;aspose.cells/</guid>
      <description>All Excel worksheets have gridlines by default. They help delineate cells, so that it is easy to enter data into particular cells. Gridlines enable us to view a worksheet as a collection of cells, where each cell is easily identifiable.
Controlling the Visibility of the Gridlines
Aspose.Cells provides a class, Workbook, that represents a Microsoft Excel file. The Workbook class contains a Worksheets collection that allows access to each worksheet in the Excel file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Display or Hide Row Column Headers in Aspose.Cells</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsnetforvsto/missingfeaturesinvsto/display&#43;or&#43;hide&#43;row&#43;column&#43;headers&#43;in&#43;aspose.cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsnetforvsto/missingfeaturesinvsto/display&#43;or&#43;hide&#43;row&#43;column&#43;headers&#43;in&#43;aspose.cells/</guid>
      <description>All worksheets in an Excel file are composed of cells that are arranged in rows and columns. All rows and columns have unique values that are used to identify them, and to identify individual cells. For example, rows are numbered – 1, 2, 3, 4, etc. – and columns are ordered alphabetically – A, B, C, D, etc. The row and column values are displayed in the headers. Using Aspose.Cells, developers can control the visibility of these row and column headers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Display or Hide Scroll Bars in Aspose.Cells</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsnetforvsto/missingfeaturesinvsto/display&#43;or&#43;hide&#43;scroll&#43;bars&#43;in&#43;aspose.cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsnetforvsto/missingfeaturesinvsto/display&#43;or&#43;hide&#43;scroll&#43;bars&#43;in&#43;aspose.cells/</guid>
      <description>Scroll bars are very used to navigate the contents of any file. Normally, there are two kinds of scroll bars:
 Vertical scroll bars Horizontal scroll bars  Microsoft Excel also provides horizontal and vertical scroll bars so that users can scroll through worksheet contents. Using Aspose.Cells, developers can control the visibility of both types of scroll bars in Excel files.
Aspose.Cells provides a class, Workbook that represents an Excel file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Display or Hide Tabs in Aspose.Cells</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsnetforvsto/missingfeaturesinvsto/display&#43;or&#43;hide&#43;tabs&#43;in&#43;aspose.cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsnetforvsto/missingfeaturesinvsto/display&#43;or&#43;hide&#43;tabs&#43;in&#43;aspose.cells/</guid>
      <description>If you closely look at the bottom of a Microsoft Excel file, you will see a number of controls. These include:
 Sheet tabs. Tab scrolling buttons.  Sheet tabs represent the worksheets in the Excel file. Click any tab to switch to that worksheet. The more worksheets in the workbook, the more sheet tabs there are. If the Excel file has a good number of worksheets you need buttons to navigate through them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encrypting Excel Files in Aspose.Cells</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsnetforvsto/missingfeaturesinvsto/encrypting&#43;excel&#43;files&#43;in&#43;aspose.cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsnetforvsto/missingfeaturesinvsto/encrypting&#43;excel&#43;files&#43;in&#43;aspose.cells/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft Excel (97 - 2007) enables you to encrypt and password protect your spreadsheets. It uses algorithms provided by a cryptographic service provider, or CSP, a set of cryptographic algorithms with different properties. The default CSP is &amp;lsquo;Office 97/2000 Compatible&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Weak Encryption (XOR)&#39;. It&amp;rsquo;s important to choose the proper encryption key length. Some CSPs don&amp;rsquo;t support more than 40 or 56 bits. That&amp;rsquo;s considered to be a weak encryption. For strong encryption, a minimum key length of 128 bits is required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Save Workbook to Text or CSV Format in Aspose.Cells</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsnetforvsto/missingfeaturesinvsto/save&#43;workbook&#43;to&#43;text&#43;or&#43;csv&#43;format&#43;in&#43;aspose.cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsnetforvsto/missingfeaturesinvsto/save&#43;workbook&#43;to&#43;text&#43;or&#43;csv&#43;format&#43;in&#43;aspose.cells/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, you want to convert or save a workbook with multiple worksheets into text format. For text formats (for example TXT, TabDelim, CSV etc.), by default both Microsoft Excel and Aspose.Cells save the contents of the active worksheet only.
The following code example explains how to save an entire workbook into text format. Load the source workbook which could be any Microsoft Excel or OpenOffice spreadsheet file (so XLS, XLSX, XLSM, XLSB, ODS and so on) with any number of worksheets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracing Precedents and Dependents in Aspose.Cells</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsnetforvsto/missingfeaturesinvsto/tracing&#43;precedents&#43;and&#43;dependents&#43;in&#43;aspose.cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsnet/plugins/asposecellsnetforvsto/missingfeaturesinvsto/tracing&#43;precedents&#43;and&#43;dependents&#43;in&#43;aspose.cells/</guid>
      <description>Complex financial worksheets, especially ones developed in collaboration, can hide the most embarrassing errors. Checking formulas for accuracy and finding the source of an error can be difficult when the formula uses precedent cells and dependent cells.
 Precedent cells are cells that are referred to by a formula in another Cell. For example, if cell D10 contains the formula =B5, cell B5 is a precedent to cell D10. Dependent cells contain formulas that refer to other cells.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>