<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Product Information on Aspose.Cells Product Family</title>
    <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellssharepoint/productinformation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Product Information on Aspose.Cells Product Family</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://roywangt.github.io/cellssharepoint/productinformation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Product Overview</title>
      <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellssharepoint/productinformation/product&#43;overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roywangt.github.io/cellssharepoint/productinformation/product&#43;overview/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the Aspose.Cells for SharePoint Documentation!
Aspose.Cells for SharePoint is a flexible solution supporting spreadsheet conversion that makes it possible to convert MS Excel documents within the Microsoft SharePoint applications.
You may convert multiple document formats, such as:
 PDF - Adobe Portable Document XLS - MS Excel 97~2003 XLSX - Office Open XML XLSM - Office Open XML for macros enabled TXT - Plain Text XML - Microsoft Excel SpreadsheetML ODS - OpenDocument Spreadsheet CSV - Comma Separated Values XLSB - Excel Binary 2007 MHtml - Multipurpose Internet Mail Extension HTML XPS - XML Paper Specification TIFF - Tagged Image File Format SVG - Scalable Vector Graphics DIF - Drawing Interchange Format  Aspose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supported File Formats</title>
      <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellssharepoint/productinformation/supported&#43;file&#43;formats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roywangt.github.io/cellssharepoint/productinformation/supported&#43;file&#43;formats/</guid>
      <description>Contents Summary
1 Supported File Formats
 ||      Supported File Formats         Format Description Load Save     XLS Excel 95/5.0 - 2003 Workbook.     XLSX Office Open XML SpreadsheetML Workbook or template file, with or without macros.     XLSB Excel Binary Workbook.     XLSM Excel Macro-Enabled Workbook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System Requirements</title>
      <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellssharepoint/productinformation/system&#43;requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roywangt.github.io/cellssharepoint/productinformation/system&#43;requirements/</guid>
      <description>Server Requirements
To install Aspose.Cells for SharePoint you need a computer running one of the following:
 Windows SharePoint Services 3.0 Microsoft Office SharePoint Server 2007 Microsoft SharePoint Server 2010 Microsoft SharePoint Server 2013  WE recommend that you installing Service Pack 2 or later for these products.
Client Requirements
You need a browser to access SharePoint sites. Aspose.Cells for SharePoint is tested with:
 Microsoft Internet Explorer Mozilla FireFox Google Chrome Safari  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluate Aspose.Cells</title>
      <link>https://roywangt.github.io/cellssharepoint/productinformation/evaluate&#43;aspose.cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://roywangt.github.io/cellssharepoint/productinformation/evaluate&#43;aspose.cells/</guid>
      <description>The evaluation version of Aspose.Cells for SharePoint has no time limit and free technical support is available for evaluation users too.
The download for both evaluation and full versions of Aspose.Cells for SharePoint is the same. Simply download Aspose.Cells for SharePoint from the download page and install it. Aspose.Cells works in evaluation mode by default.
Evaluation Version Limitations
Evaluation mode adds an evaluation warning into any exported documents. When you have purchased a license, simply install the license and it will work in licensed mode.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>