<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Feature Tour on Aspose.Cells Product Family</title>
    <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsjasperreports/gettingstarted/featuretour/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Feature Tour on Aspose.Cells Product Family</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsjasperreports/gettingstarted/featuretour/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Feature Overview</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsjasperreports/gettingstarted/featuretour/feature&#43;overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsjasperreports/gettingstarted/featuretour/feature&#43;overview/</guid>
      <description>Aspose.Cells for JasperReports is a product for exporting reports from JasperReports and JasperServer to Microsoft Excel format. Aspose.Cells for JasperReports inherits all features of the built-in exporter as well as makes up for some of the weaknesses of the original XLS renderer of JasperReports. This section provides detailed description of Aspose.Cells for JasperReports features. Click on the respective links in the table to learn more about the features.
   **Feature ** **Description **     XLS or XLSX Export Export reports as Microsoft Excel XLS format from your application without utilizing Microsoft Excel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XLS or XLSX Export</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsjasperreports/gettingstarted/featuretour/xls&#43;or&#43;xlsx&#43;export/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsjasperreports/gettingstarted/featuretour/xls&#43;or&#43;xlsx&#43;export/</guid>
      <description>Aspose.Cells for JasperReports allows you to deliver reports in the XLS and XLSX format without loss of layout or formatting. To create spreadsheets in the Microsoft Excel formats, Aspose.Cells for JasperReports relies on a built-in version of Aspose.Cells for Java, a leading spreadsheet-processing library from Aspose.
Microsoft Excel is not required to generate documents with Aspose.Cells.
A sample XLS report exported using Aspose.Cells for JasperReports
Attachments: XLS or XLSX Export-001.png (image/png)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High Fidelity to the Report Design</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsjasperreports/gettingstarted/featuretour/high&#43;fidelity&#43;to&#43;the&#43;report&#43;design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsjasperreports/gettingstarted/featuretour/high&#43;fidelity&#43;to&#43;the&#43;report&#43;design/</guid>
      <description>Aspose.Cells for JasperReports exports reports as Microsoft Excel spreadsheets that look identical to reports exported by the built-in exporters of JasperReports.
**A sample XLS report exported using Aspose.Cells for JasperReports **
**A sample XLS report exported using the built-in JasperReports exporters **
Attachments: High Fidelity to the Report Design-001.png (image/png) High Fidelity to the Report Design-002.png (image/png)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy and Lightweight Deployment</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsjasperreports/gettingstarted/featuretour/easy&#43;and&#43;lightweight&#43;deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsjasperreports/gettingstarted/featuretour/easy&#43;and&#43;lightweight&#43;deployment/</guid>
      <description>Aspose.Cells for JasperReports is an external exporter for JasperReports.
Aspose.Cells for JasperReports is provided as a single JAR file and can be easily installed on computers running JasperReports. Download it to start a trial.
To install the exporter, aspose.cells.jasperreports.jar should be copied to the JasperReports\lib directory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple and Affordable Licensing</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsjasperreports/gettingstarted/featuretour/simple&#43;and&#43;affordable&#43;licensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsjasperreports/gettingstarted/featuretour/simple&#43;and&#43;affordable&#43;licensing/</guid>
      <description>Every Aspose license comes with 1-year worth of free upgrades to any new version of the product that comes out and unlimited free technical support.
Aspose.Cells for JasperReports evaluation and paid versions are the same download. Simply download Aspose.Cells for JasperReports and install it. By default, the exporter works in evaluation mode. Evaluation mode injects watermarks into exported reports. To remove the watermark, purchase a license and follow the instructions on how to apply the license.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Class Free Technical Support</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsjasperreports/gettingstarted/featuretour/world&#43;class&#43;free&#43;technical&#43;support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsjasperreports/gettingstarted/featuretour/world&#43;class&#43;free&#43;technical&#43;support/</guid>
      <description>Aspose is renowned for its free and unlimited technical support provided directly by the developers of the products. If a new version of a product is available, or if resolving a question results in a fix, all new releases are free if you have an active subscription.
Getting Support
Forums
Aspose&amp;rsquo;s Support Forums is the place not only to resolve technical issues, but to participate in discussions with the vibrant and growing community of Aspose users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miscellaneous</title>
      <link>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsjasperreports/gettingstarted/featuretour/miscellaneous/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://192.168.1.240:1313/cellsjasperreports/gettingstarted/featuretour/miscellaneous/</guid>
      <description>Some effective features of Aspose.Cells for JasperReports are listed below:
 Aspose.Cells for JasperReports supports Microsoft Excel charts so that charts are exported as editable charts rather than static pictures. This way, users can edit the charts manually in Microsoft Excel if they need to. Aspose.Cells for JasperReports is easily integrated with JasperServer.  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>